Hitesha Patel

Senior HR Consultant

hiteahadabhi170@gmail.com +91-(816) 973-1176

SUMMARY

Dedicated & experienced in Human resource with 5 Years experiences in Talent Acquisition.

Experienced in recruitment, Sourcing, Screening, interviewing & Short listing. Havingexperience in IT & Non IT recruitment with product & service based clients.

Coordinate with hiring managers to develop and execute recruitment initiatives to source new talent for the clients.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Aspiring for a job in a growth oriented organization, where my recruiting experience and organization skills can be used for making a positive contribution in the human resources department by putting in maximum efforts.

Looking for job opportunity that offers professional development, learning experience and promotion. Where I can maintain and enhance human resources productively in an organization, developing strong manpower, identifying talent and deploying professional development programs in order to achieve organizational goals and fulfill employees' needs.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Skillventory - A Leading Talent Research Firm

Feb 2020 – Present

Senior HR Consultant

Department: Talent Acquisition.

Job Responsibilities.

- I am involved in hiring from Junior to Senior level.
- Taking care of end to end recruitment life cycle right from understanding the client's requirement till the joining date of candidates.
- Ensuring that resume appropriately reflects candidates experience and requirement.Briefing the Job details to the candidates.
- Managing recruitment life cycle that includes Sourcing, screening, interviewing, Reporting, Documentation and Closing the positions.
- Briefing candidates about the company as well as about the key responsibility areas of the profile. Assessing candidate's relevant experience, knowledge, skills, competencies, communication skills, truthfulness of CV, expected salary and notice period negotiationScheduling and coordinating interviews, preparing candidates for interviews with the clients by providing detailed information about job descriptions and expectations of clients. Joining formalities, Documentation formalities post the selection of the candidate
- .Follow up the shortlisted candidates and selected candidates till they join to

- the particular requirement of the clients.
- Sourcing, screening, short listing relevant profiles from job portals like Naukri, Monster or LinkedIn. Maintaining daily/ weekly/monthly reports such as interview status, joiner tracker, and closure tracker.

BOB Financial Solution Limited

Feb 2019 - Mar 2019

HR Officer

Department: Talent Acquisition.

Job Responsibilities.

- Sourcing quality resumes from the company careers site.
- Also shortlisted Summer Internship student's for the HR Department.Co-ordination with the vendor regarding lineups. Short Listing the resume based on the job requirement.
- Scheduling the interviews of the short listed candidate's. Maintaining excel sheet for the selected and rejected candidate's.
- Sending Interview call letter to the shortlisted candidate's.
- Responsible for posting job requirement on various portals.
- Co-ordination for the selection process of the shortlisted candidates.
- Responsible for collecting the joining Documents.

Tech Mahindra Business Services Ltd

Nov 2014 - May 2016

HR EXECUTIVE.

Department: Talent Acquisition.

Job Responsibilities.

- Done Outstation Recruitment. Analyze the quality people and contact them throughphone, email.
- Training the new HR Executive joiner about the work.
- Resourcing, Screening and short listing resume through various job portals. Scheduling the interviews of the short listed candidate's.
- Briefing candidate about the company, process and for the interview procedure.
 Responsible of posting job requirement on various portals, sending bulk sms and alsoreplying on the emails.
- Documentation verification & Salary Negotiation. Taking care of the joining formalities. Handling end to end recruitment cycle.

Firstsource Solution Ltd

Jan 2013 - Aug 2014

Department: Talent Acquisition.

HR ASSOCIATE.

Job Responsibilities.

 Part of Internal Recruitment Team & Employee Referral to ensure the dependency on external consultants is minimal. Identifying vacancies, screen, interview, extend offerings and employee on-boarding.

0

Source Of Profiles.

- Sourcing quality resumes from the referrals generated from employees & carry out firstlevel screening on shortlisted profiles. Also worked on job portals like (Monster, Nakuri & Times) for 4 months in differentteam to help that team to perform good.
- Doing End to End Recruitment
- Co-ordination of the selection process for the shortlisted candidates.
 Launching new and attract schemes for the employee to generate referral.

Interaction with employees/ Senior Management.

0

- Being part of the employee referrals program, my responsibilities include interacting on the regular basis with the employees and senior management to ensure a consistent flow of referrals from the floor.
- This involves floor visits on a regular basis to communicate with the employee and thesenior mangers about the opening as well as the schemes in order to generate as many referrals as possible from advisor population.

Other Responsibilities.

- Maintain report on the walkin and the referral trends.
- Organize events for the employees on behalf of the Employee Referrals Team.
 Attending the induction & spreading the awareness of the Employee Referral
 Team tothe new Joiners.
- Attending the Training Batches & the floor on regular intervals.

0

Unique Sharp Solution

May 2012 - Dec 2012

HR EXECUTIVE

Job Responsibilities:

- Resourcing, screening and short listing resumes through various job portals.
 Screening the candidates through telephonic interviews to understand the candidate's competency.
- Scheduling candidates for interviewing.
- Following the candidates till joining in organization. Short Listing the resume based on the job requirement.
- Conducting telephone and personal interviews with the department heads.
- Also handling a team of 5 Hr executive.

EDUCATIONS

College/school	University/Board	Degree/Standard	Passing Date
University of Mumbai	University of Mumbai	Master of Commerce	2020

Shri LP Raval College	University of Mumbai	Commerce	2019
Oriental College of Commerce & Management	University of Mumbai	Bachelor of Management Studies.	2012
Maniben Nanavati Women's College	Maharashtra State Board of Secondary and Higher Secondary Education	HSC	2009
Delhi Board	Delhi Board	SSC	2007

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Country	India	
Husband Name	Vimal Patel	
Marital Status	Married	
Gender	Female	
Languages Known	Hindi, English, Gujarati	
Address	Goregaon West, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India	

I hereby declare that all above information is in correct with fact or truth up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibilities for the correctness of the above mentioned particulars.

Place: Mumbai
 Hitesha Vimal Patel